Curriculum Vitae



Michelle Falzon

7, Triq il-Fjorin, Swieqi, SWQ 2602, Malta

+356 7909 9612

michelle_falzon@hotmail.com

About

Hello! I am an artificial intelligence graduate from the University of Malta. I am a hard working individual who always strives to improve my skills. I have worked in the iGaming industry for almost two years.

Throughout my time at Raketech, I learnt to adapt quickly, think creatively and manage a team. Within a few months in the company, I was leading a small team with various skills and backgrounds. Our aim was to improve a small network of sites by making them engaging to our target audience, fast, responsive and increase their overall SEO performance.

The rest of my experience, though unrelated to my line of work, helped me understand the qualities needed to be a good leader and team player. I have also tried my hand at voluntary work which was incredibly rewarding. It was through this type of work that I learned proper time management and coping with new challenges.

In my free time I enjoy fencing and taking part in theatrical performances, as well as, reading and gardening.

I believe that teamwork, organization, having a willingness to learn and good time management are the keys to success!

Experience

09/2017 - Present

Web Developer and Team Performance Coordinator - Raketech

- Languages used: React, Vanilla Javascript with jQuery, SQL, PHP, HTML and CSS
- Developing an internal tool for simplifying the visualization of site metrics and Search Engine Optimization (SEO) health and recommending websites from which purchased links would improve the site's overall rank metrics. This involved the use of third party APIs, React libraries, messaging queues (RabbitMQ), database design and management.
- Maintaining, designing and developing new features for loan affiliation websites with a focus on SEO
- Overseeing team performance and coordinating tasks (both in-house and with freelancers)
- Managing the acquisition of affiliation links for each site

- Maintaining the overall SEO health of the sites by abiding to the guidelines set by Google
- Working with third parties to optimize products and sales
- Minor server side jobs such as creating CRON jobs and service files
- Winner of the Ownership and Teamwork Raketech Awards
- Winner of the Hackathon Award

07/2016 - 09/2016 Intern Front End Developer - Betsson Group

- Bug fixing
- Minor testing
- Styling of new features

10/2015 - 12/2017 Attendant I.T. Services - University of Malta

- Supervising computer labs
- Troubleshooting

09/2015 - 03/2016 Junior Clerk - HLB Falzon & Falzon (Family Business)

06/2015 - 08/2015 Teen Group Leader - BELS

• Supervising foreign students ages 12 to 17 on activities.

03/2015 - 06/2015 Children's' Animator After Glow Events

- Taking care of children between the ages of 3 and 10 years old
- Dancing, Games, Balloon modelling

04/2014 - 03/2015 Children's' Animator - PartyTrap

07/2013 - 09/2013 Assistant - HLB Falzon & Falzon (Family Business)

Filing and updating archives

Education and training

2018 Informal Leadership Training - StreetHR (Malta)

2018 The Web Developer Bootcamp - Colt Steele (Udemy)

• HTML5

• CSS3

JavaScript

Bootstrap

SemanticUI

jQuery

NodeJS

NPM

ExpressJS

REST

MongoDBPassportJS

Vue JS 2 - The Complete Guide - Maximilian Schwarzmüller (Udemy)

2018

- Vue JS 2
- Vue Router
- Vuex

2014 - 2017

BSC 1CT (Artificial Intelligence - Honours) EQF level 6 - University of Malta

- Programming in Java, C, C++, HTML + CSS, Javascript, PHP, SQL, PROLOG, MATLAB
- Web Development
- Signal Processing
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Mathematics for Engineers
- Discrete Mathematics
- Databases
- Natural Language Processing
- Intelligent Agents
- Web Intelligence
- Advanced Game Al
- Entrepreneurship
- Object Oriented Programming
- Business Intelligence
- Machine Learning
- Content Based Image Retrieval and Categorization

2015

CS50 - Computer Science Introduction Course - Harvard University

- C programming
- Web Development HTML, CSS , PHP, Javascript

2012

Web Design Summer Course - STC

2012 - 2014

De La Salle College Sixth Form EQF level 4

- Advanced level: Computing and Pure Mathematics
- Intermediate level: English, Physics and Systems of Knowledge

2001 - 2012

School Leaving Certificate Level 3 - St. Joseph School

- English
 - Maltese
- Maths

PhysicsFrench

iviatiis

Trench

Biology

Religion

Computer Studies

Chemistry

Hobbies

2008 - 2017

Olympic Fencing - St. Paul Fencing Club

2012 - 2018

Drama and Theatrical Productions - DLS Productions/ KSU Students' Fest

2017 - 2018 Historical Fencing — Malta Historical Fencing Association

Other Reading, Gardening, Basketball, Baking, Gaming, Art

Voluntary Work

07/2013 - 09/2013 Volunteer - Nature Trust Malta (Malta)

• Taking care of the injured turtles at Fort Lucjan

Taking care of children and collecting donations during the 'Kids on the

Coast' events

07/2013 - 11/2013 Child-care worker - MSSP Oratory

• Taking the young children during the homily and teaching them about the

readings in a simple manner as well as planning games for them

01/2014 - 10/2014 Deputy Mayor - Swiegi Youth Local Council

2015 - 2017 Subcommittee - ICTSA (ICT Students' Association)